<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>do-calculus on Notes To An Earlier Self</title>
    <link>/tags/do-calculus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in do-calculus on Notes To An Earlier Self</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/do-calculus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Pearl&#39;s Front-Door Magic</title>
      <link>/post/2019/07/06/understanding-pearl-s-front-door-magic-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/07/06/understanding-pearl-s-front-door-magic-ii/</guid>
      <description>Do-calculus, Judea Pearl’s comprehensive algorithmic framework for causal reasoning, can intimidate even a seasoned statistician. I will try to present an intuitive justification of a couple of its common patterns – namely the back-door and, the seemingly magical, front-door adjustment formulas. Along the way I will derive the front-door formula (for a special case) from the back-door formula without invoking the rules of do-calculus.
In a previous post I attempted to explain the distinction between Bayesian and causal (or interventional) conditioning by introducing the do notation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation View of Causality</title>
      <link>/post/2019/05/18/understanding-pearl-s-front-door-magic-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/05/18/understanding-pearl-s-front-door-magic-part-i/</guid>
      <description>div.blue pre.r { background-color:azure; } div.blue pre { background-color:#ffe2dd; }  My attempt to present an intuitive account of causal reasoning and the important notions of causal conditioning and counterfactuals without resorting to some of the formalities of do-calculus, d-separation, couterfactual notation and the like. All the programs in the post will be in R, but should be accessible to readers with no experience with the language.
Causal reasoning from scientific data has undergone a quiet revolution in the past couple of decades.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>