<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Notes To An Earlier Self</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Notes To An Earlier Self</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Work Incentive - A Modest Alternative to UBI and Job Guarante</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/21/a-modest-alternative-to-ubi-and-job-guarante/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/21/a-modest-alternative-to-ubi-and-job-guarante/</guid>
      <description>Let me offer an analogy that might make the distinctions between the UBI, JG and SWI a little more stark. Like any analogy this one has its boundary of applicability which I will try not to breach.
Imagine that scientists have discovered the soils in the backyards of most homes constantly produce a chemical - let’s call it humanium - which if left underground will over a few decades degrade into toxins that cause severe societal health issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extrapolating by Inverse Optimization</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/09/extrapolating-by-inverse-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/09/extrapolating-by-inverse-optimization/</guid>
      <description>Wherein I present a simple example of a prediction problem modeled as inverse optimization, with a brief detour into Bayesian estimation.
Our story begins with Alice who runs a grocery store with a small selection of locally grown produce. Alice wishes to estimate the impacts of changing the prices of her produce on the purchase behavior of her customers and wonders if the data she has been collecting over the previous year can help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Some notes that I wish were available to me as I was trying to understand some of these topics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>