<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Notes To An Earlier Self</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Notes To An Earlier Self</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Pearl&#39;s Front-Door Magic</title>
      <link>/post/2019/07/06/understanding-pearl-s-front-door-magic-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/07/06/understanding-pearl-s-front-door-magic-ii/</guid>
      <description>Do-calculus, Judea Pearl’s comprehensive algorithmic framework for causal reasoning, can intimidate even a seasoned statistician. I will try to present an intuitive justification of a couple of its common patterns – namely the back-door and, the seemingly magical, front-door adjustment formulas. Along the way I will derive the front-door formula (for a special case) from the back-door formula without invoking the rules of do-calculus.
In a previous post I attempted to explain the distinction between Bayesian and causal (or interventional) conditioning by introducing the do notation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation View of Causality</title>
      <link>/post/2019/05/18/understanding-pearl-s-front-door-magic-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/05/18/understanding-pearl-s-front-door-magic-part-i/</guid>
      <description>div.blue pre.r { background-color:azure; } div.blue pre { background-color:#ffe2dd; }  My attempt to present an intuitive account of causal reasoning and the important notions of causal conditioning and counterfactuals without resorting to some of the formalities of do-calculus, d-separation, counterfactual notation and the like. All the programs in the post will be in R, but should be accessible to readers with no experience with the language.
Causal reasoning from scientific data has undergone a quiet revolution in the past couple of decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossvalidation and the Disappointed Optimizer</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/25/crossvalidation-and-the-disappointed-optimizer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/25/crossvalidation-and-the-disappointed-optimizer/</guid>
      <description>Wherein I introduce and explain the well-studied mechanism behind the pervasive phenomenon in life of things being just a bit worse than expected. I will walk through some of the discussion in the excellent article, The Optimizer’s Curse: Skepticism and Postdecision Surprise in Decision Analysis by Smith and Winkler.
Have you noticed that the checkout lanes you choose at the grocery store tend to be slower than you expected, the products you order off Amazon disappoint, and your second dates are not as exciting as your firsts?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extrapolating by Inverse Optimization</title>
      <link>/post/2019/03/09/extrapolating-by-inverse-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/03/09/extrapolating-by-inverse-optimization/</guid>
      <description>Wherein I present a simple example of a prediction problem modeled as inverse optimization and its formulation as a bilevel optimization problem, with a brief detour into Bayesian estimation.
Our story begins with Alice who runs a grocery store with a small selection of locally grown produce. Alice wishes to estimate the impacts of changing the prices of her produce on the purchase behavior of her customers and wonders if the data she has been collecting over the previous year can help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Some notes that I wish were available to me as I was trying to understand some of these topics. My (very) old blog is at https://mlstatold.blogspot.com/</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>